Zachary DeNoto

Data Analyst

(585) 683-8068 • Rochester, NY https://zacharydenoto.github.io/z.denoto@gmail.com

RESUME OBJECTIVE

Data Analyst with 5 + years of experience executing data-driven solutions to increase efficiency, accuracy and internal data processing. Experienced at creating and using data models for predictive analytics to deliver insights to complex business problems.

SKILLS

• Python

R

• Pandas, Scikit-learn

Tableau

Spark

Keras

Tensorflow

• SQL

Alteryx

VBA

EXPERIENCE

Peko Precision Products

Data Analyst

Rochester, NY

August 2018-Present

- Perform custom data analysis using Python, Alteryx, or VBA based on specific criteria provided by senior management or C-level executives.
- Create weekly and monthly advanced Tableau or Python visualizations using libraries such as Matplotlib, ggplot, and Plotly from data outputs based on the reports needed.
- Write Python scripts to replace manual Excel data manipulation or VBA Macros resulting in report run time from hours to seconds.
- Pull, manipulate, and join data from SQL servers using Alteryx and ERP software to integrate multiple data sources.
- Design and implement Python scripts utilizing Pandas library to alter ERP report outputs or SQL data sources to create more efficient, fast data solutions.

Arthur J Gallagher Rochester, NY

Analyst

June 2016-August 2018

- Collected, processed, and visualized data for over 20 companies moving C-level executives globally.
- Designed and programmed Excel Macros to reconcile errors in international employees' compensation documentation.
- Created custom formulas and spreadsheets in Excel to automatically input data, increasing productivity
 resulting in decreased time spent on data retrieval and input.

Paychex Rochester, NY

Risk Analyst

November 2015-May 2016

- Analyzed data patterns and statistics to determine level of risk of million-dollar payrolls.
- Gather and process client data to determine level of financial risk to company.

EDUCATION

Bellevue University

Bellevue, NE

Master of Science (MS) in Data Science

June 2021

Saint Joseph's University

Philadelphia, PA

Bachelor of Science (BS) in Leadership, Ethics and Organizational Sustainability (LEO)

May 2015